Well, if you want to get data, there's
usually four main ways to request it.
They are get, put, post, and delete. Um,
and so what are those? Well, they are
all HTTP requests. They are types of
ways of gathering your information
together and sending it over the
internet. So, um, usually we use them
for four things. Um, you use get
requests to request information and
bring it back. In other words, you go
and get the information. Um, use post
requests for creating new information.
In other words, you take your new
information and you post it out there.
Um, you use put requests for editing
existing information. And I'll let you
guess what delete does. Um, but if you
were paying attention, you may notice
that that conveniently lines up with
CRUD. So CRUD is create, retrieve,
update, and delete. If you want to
create, then you use a post request. If
you want to retrieve, you use a get
request. If you want to update, you use
a put request. And if you want to
delete, you guessed it, you use a delete
request. And so, it's important to
understand those types of requests. And
in the next video, we'll get a little
closer to making those requests from our
code. We're going to make those requests
from a browser.